He gave the West justice right up to its neck...
then rammed more down its throat.
Lawman is a western film directed by Michael Winner.
While passing through the town of Bannock, a bunch of drunken cattlemen go overboard
with their celebrating and accidentally kill an old man with a stray shot.
They return home to Sabbath unaware of his death.
Bannock lawman Jered Maddox later arrives there to arrest
everyone involved on a charge of murder.
Sabbath is run by land baron Vince Bronson, a benevolent despot, who, upon
hearing of the death, offers restitution for the incident.
Bannock Marshal Jared Maddox, played by Burt Lancaster.
Sabbath Marshal Cotton Ryan, played by Robert Ryan.
Vincent Bronson, played by Lee J. Cobb.
Vernon Adams, played by Robert Duvall.
Laura Shelby, played by Sheree North.
Harvey Stenbaugh, played by Albert Salmi.
Lawman is a 1971 American revisionist Western film produced and directed by
Michael Winner and starring Burt Lancaster, Robert Ryan, Lee J.
Cobb, Sheree North, and Robert Duvall.
The screenplay by Gerald Wilson focuses on Jered Maddox, a rigid marshal who arrives in a small town to arrest a group of cattlemen for the
accidental death of an old man, sparking a conflict between his absolute adherence to the law and the community's pragmatic desire for peace.
Filmed on location in Durango, Mexico, Lawman was Winner's
first Western and his first American production.
The film explores themes of justice, obsession, and the
changing nature of the American frontier.
It received mixed reviews upon release but has since garnered
appreciation for its moral complexity and performances.